<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The letanie and suffrages</title>
            <author>Church of England.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1558</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 11 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A06055</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 16453.7</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S4759</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">23863759</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 23863759</idno>
            <idno type="VID">26923</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A06055)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 26923)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1836:10)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The letanie and suffrages</title>
                  <author>Church of England.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[16] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1558]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by STC (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A⁸.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: stained, with print show-through.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Cambridge University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Litanies --  Church of England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="litany_and_suffrages">
            <pb facs="tcp:26923:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:26923:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>¶ The Letanie and Suffrages.</head>
            <p>O God, the father of heauen haue mercy vpon vs mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerable ſynners.</p>
            <p rend="small">O God the father of heauen: haue mercy vpon vs miſerable ſynners.</p>
            <p>O God the ſonne, redemer of the worlde: haue mercye vpon vs miſerable ſynners.</p>
            <p rend="small">O God the ſonne, redemer of the world: haue mercy vpon vs miſerable ſynners</p>
            <p>O God the holy ghoſte, proce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding from the father and the Sonne: haue mercy vpon vs miſerable ſynners.</p>
            <p rend="small">O God the holy ghoſte, procedyng from the father and the ſonne: haue mercy vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on vs miſerable ſynners.</p>
            <p>O holye, bleſſed, and glorious Trinitie, thrée perſones and one God: haue mercy vpon vs miſerable ſynners.</p>
            <p rend="small">
               <pb facs="tcp:26923:2"/>
O holye, bleſſed, and glorious Trinitye, three perſons and one God: haue mercy vpon vs miſerable ſynners.</p>
            <p>Remember not Lord our offe<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ces, nor the offe<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ces of our fore fathers, neither take thou ven<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>geau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce of our ſinnes: ſpare vs good Lorde, ſpare thy people, who<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> thou haſt redemed wyth thy moſt precious bloude, and be not angry with vs for euer</p>
            <p rend="small">Spare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>From al euil and miſchief, fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> ſinne, from the craftes and aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaultes of the deuyl, from thy wrathe, and from euerlaſtyng dampnacion.</p>
            <p rend="small">Good Lorde delyuer vs.</p>
            <p>From al blindnes of hart, fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> pride, vainglory, and Hipocri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſy, from enuy, hatred and ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lice,
<pb facs="tcp:26923:2"/>and all vncharitablenes.</p>
            <p rend="small">Good Lord delyuer vs.</p>
            <p>From fornication, and all o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther deadly ſinne, and from al the deceites of the worlde, the fleſh, and the deuyll.</p>
            <p rend="small">Good Lord delyuer vs.</p>
            <p>From lightnings &amp; tempeſts, from plage, peſtilence, and fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine from battaile, and mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, and from ſodayne death.</p>
            <p rend="small">Good Lorde delyuer vs.</p>
            <p>From all ſedicion and pryuye conſpiracie, from all falſe doc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trine and hereſye, from hard<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe of harte, and contempte of thy woorde and commaun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dement.</p>
            <p rend="small">Good Lord delyuer vs.</p>
            <p>By the miſtery of thy holy in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>carnacio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>,
<pb facs="tcp:26923:3"/>by thy holy natiuitie and circumciſion, by thy bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſme, faſting, and temptacion</p>
            <p rend="small">Good Lorde delyuer vs.</p>
            <p>By thyne agonie and bloudye ſweate, by thy croſſe and paſſi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>on, by thy precious death and buriall, by thy glorious reſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection and aſcention, &amp; by the comming of the holy ghoſt.</p>
            <p rend="small">Good Lord delyuer vs.</p>
            <p>In al time of our tribulacion, in al time of our wealth, in the houre of death, and in the daye of indgement.</p>
            <p rend="small">Good Lorde delyuer vs.</p>
            <p>We ſynners dooe beſeche thee to heare vs, O Lord God, and that it maye pleaſe thee to rule and gouerne thy holy churche vniuerſall in the right way.</p>
            <p rend="small">
               <pb facs="tcp:26923:3"/>
We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it may pleaſe the to kepe Elizabeth thy Seruaunt, our Quene and Gouernour.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it may pleaſe the to rule her hart, in thy faith, feare and loue, and that ſhe mai alwaies haue affiaunce in thee, and e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver ſeke thy honor and glory.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it may pleaſe thee to be her defe<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>der &amp; keper, giuing her the victory ouer al her enemies</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it may pleaſe thee to il<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luminate al biſhops, paſtours and miniſters of the Churche, with true knowledge and vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtanding of thy worde, and that both by their preachyng
<pb facs="tcp:26923:4"/>&amp; liuing, they may ſet it forth and ſhewe it accordingly.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it may pleaſe thee to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>due the lordes of the counſail, and al the nobiliti, with grace wiſedome, and vnderſtanding</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it maye pleaſe thee to bleſſe &amp; keepe the magiſtrates giuing them grace to execute iuſtice, and to maintain truth</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it maye pleaſe thee to bleſſe and kepe all thy people.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it maye pleaſe thee to geue to all Nacions, vnitye, peace, and concord.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſcehe thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it mai pleaſe the to giue
<pb facs="tcp:26923:4"/>vs an harte to loue and dreade thee, and diligently to liue af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter thy commaundementes.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it mai pleaſe the to giue al thy people encreaſe of grace to heare meekely thy woorde, and to receiue it with pure af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fection, and to bring forth the fruites of the ſpirite.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it maye pleaſe thee to bryng into the way of truthe, al ſuche as haue erred and are deceyued.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it maye pleaſe thee to ſtrengthen ſuche as do ſtand, and comfort &amp; help the weake harted, and to rayſe vp theym that fall, and ſmall ye to beate
<pb facs="tcp:26923:5"/>down Sathan vnder our fete,</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it may pleaſe the to ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cour, help, and comfort, al that be in daunger, neceſſitye, and tribulacion.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it may pleaſe the to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerue all that trauaile by land or bi water, al wome<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> laboring of child, al ſick perſons &amp; yong children, and to ſhew thy pity vpon all priſoners &amp; captiues.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it may pleaſe thee to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fend &amp; prouide for the father<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſſe childre<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> and widowes, and al that be deſolate &amp; oppreſſed.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it maye pleaſe thee to haue mercy vpon all men.</p>
            <p rend="small">
               <pb facs="tcp:26923:5"/>
We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lorde.</p>
            <p>That it may pleaſe the to for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giue our enemies, perſecutors and ſclaunderers, and to turne their hartes.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lord.</p>
            <p>That it may pleaſe the to giue and preſerue to oure vſe the kindly fruites of the earth, ſo that in due tyme we maye en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ioy them.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lorde.</p>
            <p>That it may pleaſe the to giue to vs true repentaunce, to for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geue vs all our, ſynnes, negli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gences and ignorau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ces, and to endue vs with the grace of thy holy ſpirit, to amend our liues accordyng to thy holy worde.</p>
            <p rend="small">We beſeche thee to heare vs good Lorde.</p>
            <p>Sonne of God, we beſeche the
<pb facs="tcp:26923:6"/>to heare vs.</p>
            <p rend="small">Sonne of God, we beſeche thee to heare vs.</p>
            <p>O lambe of God, that takeſt a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way the ſinnes of the worlde.</p>
            <p rend="small">Graunt vs thy peace.</p>
            <p>O lambe of God, that takeſt a<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>way the ſynnes of the world.</p>
            <p rend="small">Haue mercye vpon vs.</p>
            <p>O Chriſt heare vs.</p>
            <p rend="small">O Chriſt heare vs.</p>
            <p>Lord haue mercy vpon vs.</p>
            <p rend="small">Lorde haue mercye vpon vs.</p>
            <p>Chriſt haue mercy vpon vs.</p>
            <p rend="small">Chriſt haue mercye vpon vs.</p>
            <p>Lord haue mercy vpon vs.</p>
            <p rend="small">Lorde haue mercye vpon vs.</p>
            <p>Our father whych art in. &amp;c. And ſuffer vs not to be led in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to temptation.</p>
            <p rend="small">But delyuer vs from euyll. Amen.</p>
            <p>
               <label>The V<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>rſicle.</label>
               <lb/>
O Lorde deale not wyth vs after our ſynnes.</p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:26923:6"/>
               <label>The Aunſwere.</label>
               <lb/>
Neither rewarde vs after our iniquities.</p>
            <p>Let vs pray.<lb/>
O God merciful father that deſpiſeſt not the ſghyng of a contrite hart, nor y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> deſire of ſuch as be ſorowful, merci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fullye aſſiſt our prayers, y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> wee make before the in al our trou<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>bles and aduerſities, whe<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ſoe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uer they oppreſſe vs, and gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciouſly heare vs, that thoſe e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uils, which the craft and ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiltie of the deuil or man wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keth againſt vs, be brought to nought, and by the prouide<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce of thy goodnes, they maye be diſperſed, that we thy ſeruan<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tes, beyng hurt by no perſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s,
<pb facs="tcp:26923:7"/>may euermore giue than<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kes vnto thee in thy holy chur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>che: through Ieſu Chriſt our Lord. Amen.</p>
            <p rend="small">O Lorde, aryſe, helpe vs, and delyuer vs, for thy names ſake.</p>
            <p>O God, we haue heard w<hi rend="sup">t</hi> our cares, and our fathers haue de<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>clared vnto vs the noble wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kes y<hi rend="sup">t</hi> thou didſt in their daies<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and in the old tune before the.</p>
            <p rend="small">O Lorde aryſe, helpe vs, and delyuer vs, for thyne honour.</p>
            <p>Glory be to the father, and to the ſonne, and to the holy goſt As it was in the beginning is now, and euer ſhall be worlde without ende. Amen.</p>
            <p>From our enemies defend vs, O Chriſt.</p>
            <p rend="small">Graciouſly looke vpon our afflictions.</p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:26923:7"/>
Pitifully behold the dolour of our hart.</p>
            <p rend="small">Mercyfully forgeue the ſine of thy people.</p>
            <p>Fauourabli with mercy heare our prayers.</p>
            <p rend="small">O ſonne of Dauid haue mercye vpon vs.</p>
            <p>Bothe now and euer vouche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſafe to heare vs, O Chriſt.</p>
            <p rend="small">Graciouſly heare vs, O Chriſt.</p>
            <p rend="small">Graciouſly heare vs, O Lord Chriſt.</p>
            <p>
               <label>The Verſicle.</label>
               <lb/>
O Lord let thy mercy be ſhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wed vpon vs.</p>
            <p>
               <label>The Aunſwere.</label>
               <lb/>
As we do put our truſt in thee.</p>
            <p>Let vs pray.<lb/>
WE humblye beſeche thee O father, mercyfullye to looke vpon our infirmities, and for the glory of thy name ſake, tourne from vs thoſe e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uilles that we moſt ryghtouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly
<pb facs="tcp:26923:8" rendition="simple:additions"/>haue deſerued: And graunt that in all our troubles, wee may p<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ur whole truſt &amp; con<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fidence <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ercye, and euer more ſeru<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ee in holines and purenes of lyuyng to thy ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour and glorye, through our onelye mediatoure and aduo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate Ieſus Chriſt our Lorde. Amen.</p>
            <p>O God, whoſe nature and propertie is, euer to haue mercye and to forgeue, receiue oure humble peticions: and though we be tyed and bound with the chaine of our ſinnes, yet lette the pytyfulnes of thy great mercy loſe vs: for the ho<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nour of Ieſus Chriſtes ſake, our mediatour and aduocate.</p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:26923:8" rendition="simple:additions"/>
ALmighty and euerlaſting God, which onely workeſt great maruciles: ſende downe vpon our Biſſhops and cura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tes, and al congregacions co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to their charge, y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> helth<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>full ſpirite of thy grace, &amp; that they maye truelye pleaſe thee: Poure vpon them the continu<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>all dewe of thy bleſſing: grau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t this, O Lorde, for the honour of our aduo<gap reason="illegible" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd mediator Ieſus Chriſt. Amen.</p>
            <p>GRaunt we beſech thee, O almighty God, that we in our trouble put our whole con<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fidence vpon thy mercy, that we agaynſte al aduerſitie, bee defended vnder thy protection graunt this, O lorde God, for
<pb facs="tcp:26923:9"/>our onely mediatoure and ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uocate Ieſus Chriſtes ſake. Amen.</p>
            <div type="prayer">
               <head>☞ A prayer of Chriſoſtome.</head>
               <p>ALmighty GOD, which haſt giuen vs grace at this time with one accord, to make our common ſupplications vn<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>to thee, and doeſt promiſe that when two or three be gathered together in thy name, y<hi rend="sup">u</hi> wylt graunt their requeſtes: fulfyll now, O Lord, the deſires and peticions of thy ſeruauntes, as may be moſt expedient for theym: grauntyng vs in thys world, knowledge of thy truth, and in the world to com, life euerla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſting. Amen.</p>
            </div>
            <pb facs="tcp:26923:9"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
